<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>rovitotv's blog - Scouts</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/scouts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2017-06-10T20:37:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Passing of Everett Sherron A True American Hero</title><link href="/passing-of-everett-sherron-a-true-american-hero.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-10T20:37:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-10T20:37:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Todd V. Rovito</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-06-10:/passing-of-everett-sherron-a-true-american-hero.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Overview of Mr. Sherron's Work In Boy Scouts with Troop 18&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mr. Everett Sherron passed away on May 25, 2017 quietly in his sleep at age 100.
Over Everett's lifetime he has been active in Scouts, he has served with
Troop 18 since 1955.  For those mathematically challenged that is 62 years
far longer than I have been alive!  My Son Elijah Rovito and I have been with
Troop 18 for over a year plus we have seen Everett on many occasions when
Troop 18 and Pack 3019 would do events together.  Everett was a consistent
figure to our boys, every Tuesday rain, shine, or snow Everett
would appear at our weekly meeting.  Sometimes Everett would drive himself
but often times he would catch a ride with one of the other leaders.  Two
days before Everett passed away Troop 18 was blessed with Everett's
appearance for our committee meeting, Everett sat next to me on my right.  We
greeted each other and as usual Everett told me he was doing fine. I have never
heard Everett complain he would just carry on as usual doing his best.  It is
difficult to imagine with such a huge age difference but I believe our boys
appreciated Everett they would often assist Everett up and down stairs and
make sure his path was clear.  On June 3rd Troop 18 camped at Germantown
Metro Park (formally known as Camp Hook) for the Twin Valley Trails Hike event.
Camp Hook was started by Everett's Father in 1927 and was the motivation for
Everett's family to move to Middletown, Ohio from Kentucky.  Camp Hook was
the major Scout camp ground in south west Ohio until Camp Friedlander was opened
in 1991.  In 2010 Adam Stump led a Boy Scout Eagle project to place this dedication
monument and surround the tree from England with a fence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1uMZo72I87J5FJarLDzeGdvUUa4nTYsNP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Troop 18 paid their respects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XgzO5iBbAq0bC6mEQ7qL-h9m4mzSRTNb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Troop 18 got the word out about Everett's passing and Scouters had a big presence at
the visitation which was June 9th and a large turn out for the church service on
June 10th.  We organized a large color guard at the grave site and were able
to line the road up with scouts from all across Dan Beard Council.  If you were able
to make it thanks!  Here is a picture as we are getting the color guard organized:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1y0cliLfpd4AqEHItyysEkHXcyPPKbEd9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally in the picture below you can see the Troop 18 boys surrounding
Everett's grave site with flags getting ready for the service to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1zICes_ueUxvswrcyxKS4slbhgdgaA7o3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the grave site service the boys gathered around in a circle and
joined their hands over hands together with Everett's casket in the middle of the
circle and said the same prayer they always say at the end of each Troop
meeting. Indeed this was the best way for all of us to wish Everett goodbye and to thank
him for so many years of service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.journal-news.com/news/local/middletown-everett-sherron-lifetime-boy-scout-dies-age-100/yX8ZXY5Ea7DBxwANzDmMoK/"&gt;Middletown Journal Article about Everett's Passing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.whio.com/news/local/everett-sherron-100-talks-about-his-boy-scout-involvement/rh78VI4GgP2yuDZfcfRIuI/"&gt;Everett Talks about Boy Scout Involvement at 100th birthday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.legacy.com/obituaries/dayton/obituary.aspx?n=everett-sherron&amp;amp;pid=185703950&amp;amp;fhid=22484"&gt;Everett's Obituary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Pack 19 Fishing at Camp Hook</title><link href="/pack-19-fishing-at-camp-hook.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-14T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2015-12-25T12:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Todd V. Rovito</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-06-14:/pack-19-fishing-at-camp-hook.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pack 19 Fishing at Camp Hook fun summer time activity&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pack 19 and other packs from Hopewell District had a beautiful day for fishing
and other fun in the sun.  This is our Fishing Challenge: North Hopewell Cub
Scout Kick-Off to Summer event.  The fish were very "smart" with water clear
enough that allowed the boys to watch the fish.  In the picture below this is
Elijah wondering why the fish aren't biting even though he has dropped the worm
right in front of them.  Ironically in one case a fish did bite the worm and
took the half with out the hook.  Another fish took the worm and the hook but
the hook came off the line and the fish got away.  It was catch and release
anyway.  The boys had a great time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1pQaXEt-HNczE3EFf41vVmrUYForPsUAo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Speedy Air Powered Pinewood Derby Car</title><link href="/speedy-air-powered-pinewood-derby-car.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-11T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-12-25T12:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Todd V. Rovito</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-02-11:/speedy-air-powered-pinewood-derby-car.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How to make a RC air powered pinewood derby car&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the last two years my Son has been involved in Cub Scouts and Pack 19 in
Middletown Ohio puts on a heck of a Pinewood Derby. Pack 19 allows leaders and
parents to build their own cars with the hope that it will distract the parents
and let the Cub Scouts build their own car. This policy works!!!!! I am one of
those Dad’s that obsesses over the Pinewood Derby race. For the 2012 race which
was my Son’s first year I generated a good idea to create an air powered car
that was to use a rubber band but I didn’t have time to complete it. The 2013
Derby was the debut year of the Speedy Air Powered Pinewood Derby Car!!!! Design
changes were made after speaking with a few engineers at AFRL over lunch. The
use of radio controlled (RC) parts made this project possible and fairly easy to
construct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="{attach}/MediaFiles/SpeedyAirPoweredPinewoodDerbyCar/pinewoodderbycarconstruction-225x300.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the picture above you can see the car being constructed. We used the
following parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two blocks of pinewood from the standard kit. One block was the car body and the other block was used to build an motor mount&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R/C Speed Controller&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R/C Receiver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R/C Motor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not shown in the picture above battery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spektrum DX6i transmitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 inch 2/3 propeller (buy a bunch of these because a few of these will be broken during testing and construction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After construction and a few test runs and tweaking the car is shown in the
picture below in its transportation box:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="{attach}/MediaFiles/SpeedyAirPoweredPinewoodDerbyCar/pinewoodderbycarinbox.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes I used rubber bands to hold the car together. This is a bad idea especially
for our track which doesn’t have the best stop mechanism. A few times during the
race I had to realign the parts and apply the rubber bands again. Below is a
picture of all the cars before the start of the race, the Speedy Air Powered
Pinewood Derby car is in the front right of the picture. I was really worried
about the bunny car because it looked fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="{attach}/MediaFiles/SpeedyAirPoweredPinewoodDerbyCar/pinewoodderbycompetition.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not shown on the table above another powered car made a appearance at the race
(below) but this Dad had solder problems so we didn’t get to race until the end.
Please take note I am not the only parent obsessed with the Pinewood Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="{attach}/MediaFiles/SpeedyAirPoweredPinewoodDerbyCar/pinewoodderbycompetitionanotherpoweredcar.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are some bad movies. It was difficult to control the throttle and take
movies on my iPhone at the same time. Needless to say this car was very fast. I
rarely had to apply much throttle to win. The car weighed in at exactly 5 oz and
was the exact size and dimensions as required. It was fun to build and even more
fun to race. Thanks to all the people that pitched in I couldn’t of done it
without your help and encouragement!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to vidoes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="{filename}/MediaFiles/SpeedyAirPoweredPinewoodDerbyCar/MovieRacing.MOV"&gt;Movie Racing Large video file 32 MB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="{filename}/MediaFiles/SpeedyAirPoweredPinewoodDerbyCar/PinewoodDerby2013UpTheTrack.m4v"&gt;Pinewood Derby 2013 Up the Track 3.2 MB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry></feed>